I LONG FOR A PEACEFUL LIFE
(我渴望得到安稳的生活)
I was born with the Evil Eye.
但我生来就具有“亚眼”
A peaceful life is ultimately a luxury for me.
安稳的生活对于我来说 终究是奢望
I was sold by my parents to the wizards in the royal palace.
我被父母卖给了王宫的魔法师们
As a necromancer,
作为死灵术士
I constantly participated in the battle.
我不停地奔走在战场上
Therefore,
正因如此
for a long time before the downfall of the country,
在国家灭亡前的很长一段时间里
I had always
我一直
wanted to live a quiet and peaceful life.
都想要过上安静平稳的日子
I long for a peaceful life,
我渴望得到安稳的生活
even if it's an illusion
即便是虚假的也好
or it's temporary.
即便是过家家也罢
I just hope to have
我不过是希望得到
the peaceful life that still lingers in my memory.
仍隐约残留在记忆中的安稳生活罢了
A peaceful life.
安稳的生活
I long for a peaceful life.
我只是想要得到安稳的生活
That's all I want.
仅此而已
They have been infected.
他们已经被玷污了
Eliminate their souls.
消灭他们的灵魂
We cannot let these souls be used by the necromancer.
不能让这些灵魂为死灵使所用
Please grant them redemption.
请给予他们救赎吧
Grant redemption to the infected children.
请给予被玷污的孩子们救赎吧
The more I desire, the more I cannot obtain.
我愈是渴望便愈是求而不得
So I started my revenge.
于是我便开始了我的报复
I spent hundreds of years on it.
我花了上百年的时间
We are wrong.
是我们错了
Please grant us redemption.
所以 请给予我们救赎吧
We are so pitiful.
给予可悲的我们救赎吧
Please kill us.
求求你了 杀掉我们吧
I don't know if it was the screams of those guys
不知是否是被那些家伙们的悲鸣
or my necromancy magic that attracted them.
以及我的死灵魔法所吸引而来
Gradually, the mine where I was hiding
渐渐的 我隐居的矿坑
turned into a maze of crawling undead.
变成了丧尸蠕动的迷宫
But even so,
但即便如此
I still long for a peaceful life.
我依旧渴望得到安稳的生活
So I've been waiting.
所以 我一直在等待
I spent decades, even centuries waiting
我花了数十年甚至数百年的时间
for someone to kill me,
等待着能够将无法自杀的我
who cannot commit suicide.
给杀掉的人出现
After that, the resurrection magic succeeded,
之后 转生的魔法成功了
so
所以
I cannot just die here
我不能在这里
for no reason.
莫名其妙地死掉
Why did she die so easily?
她怎么这么轻易就死掉了
It was just one stab in the abdomen.
不过是腹部被刺穿了一次而已啊
Didn't she have any healing potions
难道她既没有带恢复药剂
or auto-healing magic items?
也没带自动治疗的魔法道具吗？
This is bad.
这下可糟了
Where am I?
这里到底是哪里
I killed her
我竟在没有打听出情报之前
before I could gather any information.
就把她给杀掉了
No, instead of gathering information,
不 比起打听情报
I should ensure my own safety first.
我更应该先确保自身的安全
If that's the case, I can't even prove that
这样下去 我甚至都没法证明
my actions were in self-defense against the assassin.
我这是对暗杀者采取的正当防卫
If I'm pursued by guards,
如果遭到卫兵的追击
my desired peaceful life will be ruined again.
我渴望的安稳生活就又要泡汤了
By the way,
对了
just now I said something like,
我刚才还对着尸体
"All right, let's continue."
说什么“好了 让我们继续吧”…
(Dead Mount, Death Play)
《尸体如山的死亡游戏》
Is my head
我的脑袋真的坏掉了吗
Hey.
喂
It's been so long. Why hasn't it been resolved yet?
这么久了 事情怎么还没办好
Did you encounter any trouble again?
又遇上什么麻烦了吗
Oh, Clarissa.
啊啊 克拉丽莎
It's even worse.
比麻烦更严重 系统已经崩溃了
I'm sending the footage over now.
我现在把视频的档案发过去给你
Footage?
视频？
After you watch it, let me know what happened.
你看完后再告诉我到底出了什么状况
Let me know if I have gone crazy
看看到底是我疯了
or if Shinjuku has gone crazy.
还是新宿疯了
Misaki, Misaki.
美咲 美咲
Misaki is so cute.
美咲真可爱啊
Misaki really loves to smile.
美咲真的很爱笑呢
It's a good thing to love to smile.
爱笑是好事
Your smile
你的笑容
will definitely bring happiness to others.
一定会为他人带来幸福
You need to become happy with everyone.
你要和大家一起变得幸福哦
Mi…sa…ki…
美…咲…
Hey, hey, do you remember who I am?
喂喂 你还记得我是谁吗？
You... you're…
你 你这家伙是
Zaki, are you the Assassin Hunter Zaki?
“咲” 你是“杀手猎人”咲吗
You're right.
你答对了
But there's something wrong.
不过 有哪里不对哦
Darn it, don't think that just because you have gained Clarissa's appreciation,
可恶 别以为你得到克拉丽莎的赏识
Uncle, you've been killing too many people who aren't our targets.
大叔 你最近 杀了太多我们目标以外的人
So she sent me to kill you.
所以她让我来解决掉你
In my opinion,
我看到了哦
you actually find pleasure in killing.
你杀人的时候看起来超级开心的
How do you feel now?
你现在感觉怎么样
You are about to be killed by me? Are you happy?
即将被我杀掉的大叔 你觉得幸福吗
Do you think
现在的我
I look as happy now
是否和那时的你
as you did back then?
看起来一样幸福呢？
Are you from the Sakimiya family…
你这家伙 莫非是崎宫家的…
Are you here to seek revenge on me,
你这是在找我报仇吗
or are you pretending to be a righteous partner
还是说 你是专门挑一些杀手
or people from the underworld?
你是打算靠这样成为正义的伙伴吗
You're such a hypocrite.
你这个伪善者
No, no, that's not it.
不对不对 不是这样的唷
When I saw you killing people, I started thinking
我呢 在看到你杀人后就在思考
whether taking other people's life
夺去他人的性命
can make one happy?
是那么开心的一件事吗
The reason I hunt assassins
我之所以对杀手进行猎杀
is because I find it interesting.
是因为我觉得这样很有趣
That's it.
仅此而已
By the way,
不过说起来
I need to confirm one thing.
我还得确认一件事
Am I killing a good guy?
我是不是在杀一个“好人”呢？
Are you a good guy?
你是好人吗
Yes, I…
没 没错 我…
No way!
你是个好人才怪咧
It's her, right?
就是她吧
The killer named Zaki.
那个叫“咲”的杀手
That strange girl who smiles while killing people.
就是那个面带微笑杀人的怪女孩
Why did Miss Clarissa take in that kid?
克拉丽莎小姐为什么要收容那种小鬼
Do you want to take on this mission?
你想接下这项委托？
This guy is not a killer.
这个人可不是杀手
He's just a kid.
他只是个孩子
It's okay.
嗯 没关系
Anyway, I've already achieved my life goal.
反正我已经达成人生目标了
I want to confirm
我只是想要确认一下
how abnormal
自己究竟有多么不正常
I killed him.
这下把他也杀掉了呢
I can indeed
我这人果然
kill anyone,
不论对方是好是坏
regardless of whether they are good or bad.
我都下得去手啊
Living in this world is terrible
像我这样的人
for people like me.
活在世上是件很糟糕的事吧
No one can achieve happiness.
任何人都无法获得幸福
Whether they're good guy, bad guy, or Clarissa,
无论是好人还是坏人 亦或是克拉丽莎
Kuruya, Hagane,
匠匠 小钢
and me,
还有我
it is impossible for us to achieve happiness.
一定都没法获得幸福
I only have one thing left to try.
我还剩下一件没有尝试过的事情了
That's killing myself.
那就是自己杀掉自己
Hello?
喂喂？
It's me, Kuruya.
是我 缲屋
What's up, Kuruya?
怎么了 匠匠
I'm enjoying the peak
我正在享受人生的最高潮呢
I can see that.
嗯 我都看到了
Ah, I see the drone.
啊 我看到你了
If you want to die, go ahead.
想死的话随你便
But wait until you finish the job first.
但你得等到完成工作之后再去死
The kid
刚才被你割断喉咙的小鬼
is now walking around like nothing happened.
如今正像个没事人似的走在大街上
What?
什么什么？
Are you saying I didn't kill that kid?
你的意思是我没能杀掉那个孩子？
That's right.
没错
You haven't finished your job yet.
你的工作还没有做完
Huh? What's going on?
奇怪 这是怎么回事
I remember talking to Kuruya
我记得刚才和匠匠聊过这件事
Ah, so what I saw earlier
啊 原来是这样
was just an illusion?
我刚才见到的就是所谓的跑马灯？
Great, you're finally awake.
太好了 你终于醒了
It looks like I succeeded.
看来我成功了呢
But why? My abdomen was stabbed.
为什么 我的腹部可是被刺穿了啊
I died, right?
那个 我是死掉了 对吧？
Why am I alive?
为什么我又活过来了
No,
不是的
you didn't come back to life.
你没有复活
It's more like you were reborn with magic.
应该说是你借助魔法 实现了重生这件事
So,
话说
what's the situation here?
这到底是什么状况
Clarissa.
克拉丽莎？
Clarissa from intermediary agency.
“中介屋”的克拉丽莎
Why are you here?
你为什么会在这里
Your body are cold,
身体冰冷
and your pulse has stopped completely.
脉搏也已经完全停止
Verification is done.
确认完毕
You are definitely dead.
你已经死透了
Let me think... You're a zombie,
我想想 我该怎么用你们这里的语言来表达…
according to the language here.
对了 你现在是僵尸
Hey guys, are you all okay?
乖宝宝们 大家还好吗
Although this is a document that
虽说这是我随手
I recorded at random,
记录下来的文字资料
if anyone sees it,
可如果有谁看到了
I've probably gone crazy by that time.
那时我多半应该已经疯掉了吧
40 MINUTES BEFORE MISAKI SAKIMIYA WOKE UP
(崎宫美咲苏醒前40分钟)
My name is Takumi Kuruya.
我的名字叫缲屋匠
I'm a good guy in Shinjuku.
是个扎根新宿的大好人
I engage in selling information
我借助网络和无人机
by using the internet and drones.
在做买卖情报的生意
Of course, I don't have a flying license.
当然我并未拿到飞行许可
But for some reason,
因为某些缘故
I also help killers
我也会帮助杀手
hide bodies and the like.
做点隐藏尸体之类的事情
Overall, I plan to
总而言之 我是打算小心谨慎地生活的
and cautiously
今后我也是同样的打算
But why did things turn out like this?
可现在事情为什么会变成这样
Sorry to interrupt your data collection.
妨碍你们的约会真是抱歉
Polka Shinoyama.
四乃山波尔卡
May I call you that?
我可以这样称呼你吧
Before I formally greet you, I have a question for you.
在正式打招呼之前 我有话要问你
What are you doing?
你那是在做什么
Kuruya, what's going on?
匠 那是怎么回事？
That's not me.
那不是我搞的
I haven't been able to control the drone since earlier.
我从刚才开始就没办法操控无人机了
Can a drone fly
无人机可以不发出任何声音就飞起来吗
That's impossible.
怎么可能？
Please wait a moment.
请稍等一下
I'll fix her.
我现在就把她“修好”
It doesn't appear to be
这看起来 并不像是匠制作的CG画面
If I could make that kind of thing,
我要是能做出那种东西
I could make a living off this skill.
我早就靠那门手艺吃饭了
She should wake up soon.
她应该过不久就能醒过来了
Who are you guys?
你们是什么人
We're friends of that child, Misaki.
我们是那孩子 也就是美咲的朋友
We planned to take over Misaki's job
我们原本是打算来这里 接管美咲的工作
and get revenge for her.
并为她报仇的
Can I assume she's still alive?
我可以认为她还活着吗
Well, her current state is a bit complicated.
那个 她现在的状态有些微妙
Although I only did a simple procedure,
虽然我只进行了简单的处理
her brain and soul are fine now,
但她的脑髓和灵魂都已经没事了
and her body has been fixed.
她的肉体也已经修复好了
Later, when she wakes up,
之后只要在她醒过来时
we just need a sorcerer to cast a resurrection magic,
让术士施展复生魔法
and she can come back to life.
她就能活过来了
I'm talking about resurrection magic.
我说的就是复生魔法啊
Magic.
魔法？
There is indeed such knowledge in this body.
这具身体里的确存在这样的知识啊
Something like a resurrection or revival spell.
类似恢复或者复苏什么的
Are you talking about a spell in a video game?
你说的是电子游戏里的咒文吧
Denji Yuki?
典滋由喜？
Excuse me, is there anyone in this country
请问 这个国家里是否存在
who can use magic or divine technique?
能够使用魔法或是神灵术的人？
As far as I know,
据我所知
only you in front of me at the moment.
只有此刻在我面前的你能够使用
What about other countries?
其他国家呢？
There are a bunch of guys who claim to be magicians,
倒是有一堆自称为魔术师的家伙
but I've never heard of that %&$ Empire
那*&%帝国 以及￥@#王国的事情呢
or ¥@# Kingdom.
我从没听说过这两个地方
How did you pronounce what you just said?
你刚才的话 是怎么发音出来的？
What you guys just saw is a collective hallucination.
你们刚才看到的是集体幻觉
Do you think you can fool me with that?
你以为这样就能糊弄过去吗？
Hallucinations are really scary.
幻觉真是可怕啊
I couldn't fool you?
我没能糊弄过去吗
You monster.
你这个怪物
I can't understand
我反倒是弄不明白
how fragile you guys are
你们究竟有多脆弱
and how easy it is to kill you.
还有杀掉你们到底有多容易
What should I do?
我该怎么办呢
Can you give me some time to think?
你能给我点时间考虑一下吗
You're really calm.
她还真是够淡定的
Okay, I'll wait for you.
我知道了 那我就等你一下吧
He actually agreed.
他居然同意了
Doesn't this guy have any sense of nervousness?
这家伙都没有紧张感的吗
No. Should I say he's just too experienced?
不 应该说他是游刃有余吗
The weapons these people are holding
这些人手里拿着的
are very similar to the ones used by the Imperial Gorgeous Unit.
和帝国绚烂队使用的武器
It's really scary.
十分相似 真可怕
Should I run or fight?
我该逃跑还是战斗呢
Do I still have enough magic?
我魔力还够用吗
What should I do?
我该怎么办
The sound of the fire truck is so close.
消防车的声音 听起来好近
I don't know why there are many fire accidents lately.
不知道为什么 最近很多这种事
There is a fire at the Shakuzawa Building.
酌泽大楼发生了火灾
My camera can capture it.
可以连接我的摄像头看画面哦
Shakuzawa Building.
酌泽大楼…
I'm really worried about the kids,
虽然我很担心孩子们
but all we can do now
可现在也只能交给消防来处理了
What's on the screen?
那块板子上在动的是什么？
It's the fire.
如你所见 是火灾
Why did you say that you worried about the kids?
“担心孩子们”是什么意思
There's an unlicensed kindergarten
酌泽大楼里
in the Shakuzawa Building
有无证经营的幼稚园
for kids whose mom
那是为诸如母亲从事接客行业
works in the service industry
或者跟黑道扯上关系而父母双亡
or whose parents died because they got involved with the underworld.
的孩子们提供照顾的地方
I hope you can take me there right away.
我希望你们能够立刻带我过去
If you don't know where the building is,
既然你不知道大楼在哪里
then it's not your problem, right?
也就说明这件事跟你没关系 是吧
Why do you care about this?
你为何要在意这件事
I've been burned a few times before,
我曾经被烧过几次
and it's an extremely painful experience.
那是痛苦至极的体验
Kids shouldn't have to endure that kind of pain.
那不是小孩子应该承受的痛苦
Okay.
好吧
Kuruya, show him the way.
匠 给他带路
He might run away halfway through.
他可能半途就逃掉了啊
So you have to keep an eye on him.
所以你得负责监视他
That is it.
就是那里
Wait!
等 等一下
What's up with that guy?
那家伙是怎么回事
He's gotten a lot stronger as compared to
他跟躲避美咲追杀的那时候比起来
when he was running away from Misaki.
变厉害了很多
I see it. That's the building.
我看到了 就是那栋大楼
Now I can enhance my Evil Eye with magic,
现在我能够借助魔力增强亚眼的力量
and I can also sense the kids' life.
还能够感知到孩子的生命力
Fire trucks and onlookers
话说这里已经被消防车
have surrounded the area. What should…
和看热闹的人围起来了 要怎么才能进去…
Did something fly in just now?
刚才是不是有东西飞进去了？
I didn't see it.
我没看到啊
Are you the parents of those kids?
你们是那些孩子的父母吗
Please help me out.
那就请你们助我一臂之力吧
Hey, hey, the fire is spreading too fast.
喂喂 火势蔓延得太快了吧
Is there something up there?
上面好像有什么东西
What is it?
那是什么啊
Daddy?
爸爸？
It was really hot just now,
我刚才明明就很热
but now it's not hot or uncomfortable at all.
现在却一点也不热 也不觉得难受了
It's because of my dad's warm hand.
是爸爸温暖的手
Was there something powerful
刚才烟雾里
in the smoke just now?
是不是有什么不得了的东西
Even though the kids were eventually rescued,
虽说孩子们最终都被救出来了
would a normal person do that kind of thing in front of onlookers?
可正常人会当着 围观群众的面做那种事吗
And he flew out just like when he went in,
而且他和进去时一样
with a bang.
“砰”的一声就飞出来了
I cannot understand
话说这家伙的伦理观
this guy's ethics?
是怎么回事啊
He treated Misaki's life
他将美咲的生命
like a toy
当作玩具一样玩弄
and now he's trying to save a kid.
现在却跑来救小孩子
That's such a huge contrast.
这反差怎么这么大
It's so hard to understand.
真是难以理解
I don't get what he's thinking.
搞不明白他在想什么
He just seems different from us.
总感觉他和我们不一样
This guy is definitely a monster
这家伙果然是那种
that we can't associate with.
不能扯上关系的怪物啊
Maybe.
也许是这样吧
Misaki
不过 美咲现在快醒了
You need to go back to the abandoned building right away.
你给我立刻返回废弃大楼
Really?
真的假的
She's about to wake up? Are you kidding me?
快醒了？你没骗我吧？
What's going on now?
什么什么 现在是什么情况
Hey, you said I was dead,
喂喂 你们说我死掉了
what's the matter?
到底是怎么回事
I don't understand. Please tell me.
我搞不明白啊 告诉我是怎么回事吧
But on another note,
不过话说回来
even in a developed country,
即便是如此发达的国家
there are unfortunate and difficult situations for children.
也有遭遇不幸 以及处境艰难的小孩子啊
How to live a peaceful life
在这个国家
in this country?
要怎样做才能得到安稳的生活
It depends on
这得取决于你口中的“安稳”
what you mean by peaceful life.
究竟指的是什么
Personally,
我想 就个人而言
I think money
若想过得“安稳” 必不可少的东西
is essential for a peaceful life.
那就是金钱哦
She's materialistic.
她也太现实了
Is money essential in every country?
金钱 无论在哪个国家都是一样的吗
Who are you?
你究竟是什么人
Let me put it this way.
不 我还是换种问法吧
What's your wish?
你的愿望是什么
What do you want to do in this city?
你想要在这座城市里做什么
Even though I don't know anything about this place,
虽然我对这里一无所知
if I'm the only one
但是 如果…
who can use Spirit of Dead Thread,
这里只有我能够使用死灵术的话
I want to make money with it.
我想靠这个赚钱
I want a peaceful life,
我比任何人都想要获得
power that can prevent others from interrupting,
不会有人可以打扰我的
In that case,
既然如此
let me help you.
我就帮你一把好了
My name is Lisa Kuraki,
我叫仓木丽莎
and I work in intermediary agency in Shinjuku.
在新宿这边做“中介屋”的工作
It looks like
看样子
Polka Shinoyama isn't the one inhabiting this body.
寄宿在这具身体里的 并不是四乃山波尔卡
Let me be your middleman
就由我来充当不知来自何处的你
with this city.
和这座城市之间的中间人吧
In order to help you get familiar with this city,
为了让你熟悉这座城市
I will lend you my good assistants,
我会把我的好帮手借给你
Misaki and Kuruya.
也就是美咲和匠
Let me be your middleman
就由我来充当不知来自何处的你
with this city.
和这座城市之间的中间人吧
In order to help you get familiar with this city,
为了让你熟悉这座城市
I will lend you my good assistants,
我会把我的好帮手借给你
Misaki and Kuruya.
也就是美咲和匠
Why did things turn out this way?
所以说 事情为什么会变成这样
(Episode 3: The Necromancer)
(第3集 The Necromancer -死灵术士-)